Finding aid to the Department of American Studies Records CA.MS.00133
Smith College Archives
Department of American Studies Records
1950-2012
Smith College Archives
Smith College. Dept. of American Studies.
CA.MS.00133
3.583 linear feet (8 containers)
This collection contains course syllabi, announcements, invitations, newsletters, pamphlets, newspaper articles, exam questions, a handbook, and student assignments.
Biographical / Historical
American Studies was first introduced at Smith College as an interdepartmental major with the 1970-1971 academic year. Prior to this, courses were offered in various departments on campus, including English and History.
Scope and Contents
The American Studies Department records contain materials describing the classes, events, and offerings of the department. Types of materials include course syllabi, announcements, invitations, newsletters, pamphlets, newspaper articles, exam questions, a handbook, and student assignments about their ephemera collections.
Related Material
Accession 91A-146, Program Files, 1957-1987
Accession 91A-221, Program Files, 1986-1990
Accession 91A-242, Program Files, 1978-1990
Accession 97A-6, AMS 350a Fall 1996
These are unprocessed records/files and portions may be restricted. There are no box listings for these accessions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The American Studies Department records were created by the department and students in particular classes. The records were transfered to the College Archives over a period of time.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation.
Student academic records, student disciplinary records, and all records containing FERPA-covered student information are closed during the lifetime of the student. Student records created 100 years or more ago are assumed to be about deceased students.
In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)
Smith College. Dept. of American Studies.
- Course syllabi, 1950s; 2001 (Box 1137.2, Folder 1)
- Department announcements, 1960; 1990s (Box 1137.2, Folder 2)
- Diploma Program: Index to Theses, 1980-2003 (Box 1137.2, Folder 3)
- Newsletters, pamphlets, announcements, exams, newspaper articles, handbook, 1970s-1990s (Box 1137.2, Folder 4)
- Student descriptions of Ephemera collections, 1994-1995 (Box 1137.2, Folder 5)
- American Studies newsletter, 1995 (Box 1137.2, Folder 6)
- First Year Seminar "Scribbling Women", 2000-2007 (Box 1138.2, Box 1138.3, Box 1138.4)
- First Year Seminar "Scribbling Women" (RESTRICTED) (Box 1138.5)
- First Year Seminar "Scribbling Women" (Box 1155.1)
- First Year Seminar "Turning Points", 2012 (Box 1155.2)
- T-Shirts (Box 1138.1)